Mahmut Demir

Istanbul, TURKEY 90.542.698.8023 http://www.mahmutdemir.info/ mahmutdemir@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

I have a long standing passion for Robotics with proven experience. My knowledge in the field relies not only on the academic studies conducted in several prominent robotics research laboratories but also on the professial experience of working in a R&D company which built the first Tactical UAV in Turkey as well as on the handson experience acquired through both individual and team projects completed in our makerspace of which I am the co-founder of. Upon completion of my M.S. degree, I would like to continue as a PhD student in Robotics and Computer Vision areas. I am a Green Card holder and permanent resident in US.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Electrical Engineering,

2014 - Exp.2016

Bogazici University, Istanbul, TURKEY

Exchange Student,

2010 - 2011

Waseda University, Tokyo, JAPAN

B.Sc. in Electrical Engineering,

2006 - 2012

Bogazici University, Istanbul, TURKEY

PUBLICATIONS (Submitted) Mahmut Demir, H. Isıl Bozma. "Place Detection & Segments Summary Graphs." International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2016

> Mahmut Demir, H. Isıl Bozma. "Video Summarization via Segments Summary Graphs." Workshop on the Video Summarization, International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2015

> (Best Paper Award) Mahmut Demir, H. Isıl Bozma. "Yer Sezimleme ve Ozet Bolut Cizgeleri." Turkiye Robotbilim Konferansı (TORK), 2015

RESEARCH **EXPERIENCE**

Researcher

Sep.2012 - Mar.2013

Cognitive Robotics Laboratory, Sabanci University, Istanbul, TURKEY

- Redesigned ROS navigation package to utilize holonomic motion capability of KUKA youBot robots.
- Developed an application to recognize shiny surfaced kitchen utensils.

Undegraduate Researcher

2008 - 2012

Intelligent Systems Lab, Bogazici University, Istanbul, TURKEY

• Undergraduate thesis: "Multi Robot Exploration and Mapping." Constructed 5 small scale robots capable of vision based navigation, tele-operation and multirobot communication.

Undergraduate Researcher

Spring 2011

Takanishi Humanoid Robotics Lab, Waseda University, Tokyo, JAPAN

 Redesigned HMM based hand gesture recognition algorithm and developed QT based interface for gesture training.

Undergraduate Researcher

Summer 2010

CMU Biorobotics Lab, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

• Implemented an optical-flow based approach to extract egomotion information of the mobile robot. Worked under the supervision of Prof. Howie Choset

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research & Teaching Assistant

Sep.2014 - Present

Bogazici University, Istanbul, TURKEY

- Master's thesis: "Vision Based Place Detection and Recognition"
- T.A. for selected courses: RobotControl, Artificial Intelligence, Numerical tools for EE Students, Energy Conversion and Electric Machines

UAV Software Engineer

May.2013 - Aug.2014

Baykar Aerospace Company, Istanbul, TURKEY

- The company, in which I worked as a part of the software team, built the first and most advanced Unmanned Aircraft in Turkey and currently being used by Turkish Armed Forces.
- My main contributions: Embedded programming for safety critical applications. Designed and programmed the smart power control, smart battery charge and monitor units. Wrote an embedded program and simulation software for controlling the aircraft motor for normal operation and in case of emergency situations.

Co-Founder Feb.2012 - Jan.2014

Base-Istanbul Makerspace, Istanbul, TURKEY

• Founded the first community-operated co-working space located in Istanbul, Turkey. Lead the community there to create and collaborate on technology, DIY and start-up projects by means of organizing several hackathons, workshops and lectures

Software Developer

Feb.2012 - Oct.2012

AveaLabs, Istanbul, TURKEY

- Developed an EKF based traffic estimation algorithm, generates a traffic report based on crowdsourced GPS data of the mobile phone users.
- Created "the SmartBox", a raspberry powered gadget, that connects internet and displays live feeds, e-mails and notifications.

SKILLS

Languages: Turkish (Native), English (Fluent), Japanese (Intermediate)

Programming Languages: C, C++, Python, Java, Matlab

Programming Libraries: OpenCV, ROS, Android

Safety Critical Embedded Programming

AWARDS

2015, Best Paper award in National Robotics Conference, TORK

2015, Turkish Government Graduate Scholarship Awardee

2006, Ranked 6th out of 1.5 Million Students at 2006 University Entrance Exam

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES Base-Istanbul Makerspace, Co-Founder, Member

Feb.2012 - Jan.2014

REFERENCES

Bogazici~University: Prof. Isil Bozma • bozma@boun.edu.tr

Baykar Aerospace Company: CTO, Selcuk Bayraktar \bullet selcuk@baykarmakina.com

Sabanci University: Prof. Mustafa Unel • munel@sabanciuniv.edu Carnegie Mellon University: Prof. Howie Choset • choset@ri.cmu.edu Waseda University: Prof. Atsuo Takanishi • takanisi@waseda.jp